<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<metadata>
	<idinfo>
		<citation>
			<citeinfo>
				<origin>Colorado Geological Survey</origin>
				<pubdate>July 2008</pubdate>
				<title Sync="TRUE">Colorado_Geothermal_Gradient_Datapoints</title>
				<geoform Sync="TRUE">vector digital data</geoform>
				<serinfo>
					<sername>Map Series</sername>
					<issue>46</issue>
				</serinfo>
				<pubinfo>
					<pubplace>Denver</pubplace>
					<publish>Colorado Geological Survey</publish>
				</pubinfo>
				<onlink>\\CGS-6YQQKF1-LXP\C$\Documents and Settings\WatterNi\My Documents\CGS Projects\Geothermal\MS46 Gradient Map Publication\Final Publication\CD contents\GIS data\Geodatabase\MS 46, Geothermal Gradient Map - GIS data.mdb</onlink>
				<lworkcit>
					<citeinfo>
						<origin>Colorado Geological Survey</origin>
						<pubdate>November 2008</pubdate>
						<title>Interpretive Geothermal Gradient Map of Colorado</title>
					</citeinfo>
				</lworkcit>
				<ftname Sync="TRUE">Colorado_Geothermal_Gradient_Datapoints</ftname></citeinfo>
		</citation>
		<descript>
			<abstract>
The Colorado Geothermal Gradient Datapoints feature class represents calculated geothermal gradient values from wells  and drillholes in Colorado as presented in the Colorado Geological Survey publication Interpretive Geothermal Gradient Map of Colorado, Map Series 46. The datapoints in this feature class were assembled from various well and drillhole data sources and gradient values were calculated in accordance to the methodology discussed below and in greater detail in the text report accompanying the Map Series 46 publication.

Map Series 46, Interpretive Geothermal Gradient Map of Colorado is a compilation of geothermal gradient data in Colorado.  Thermal gradient is the change in temperature over distance.  In geothermal resource assessment, distance is the depth into the Earth provided by a borehole or well.  Geothermal gradient is commonly expressed in units of degrees Celsius per kilometer (°C/km) or degrees Fahrenheit per 100 feet (°F/100 ft).  Geothermal gradient values are a way to quantify the depth-temperature relationship for use in evaluating geothermal resource potential.

Geothermal gradients are calculated from measurements made in drilled wells. The data shown on this map were derived from several sources - dedicated geothermal test holes, mineral resource assessment drillholes, oil, gas and CO2 wells, and geothermal wells.  Not all oil and gas well data were used in compiling the map.  Bottom-hole temperature data for the major oil and gas producing areas of Colorado were used as compiled by Dixon (2002, 2004).  In oil and gas production areas not covered by the Dixon compilations, the database was augmented by selecting oil and gas wells that had drill-stem test temperature data from the PI/Dwights dataset (IHS Energy) and temperature log data from LogSleuth (M.J. Systems). Heat flow data compiled by Blackwell and Richards (1989) and from the International Heat Flow Commission, Global Heat Flow Database for geothermal test holes and mineral resource drillholes are also contained in the database.  Heat flow data are located primarily in the mountainous central and western portion of the state, and are geographically complimentary to the oil and gas dataset.  By combining these datasets, a more complete and detailed picture of geothermal gradient in Colorado is produced than was previously available. Data points are shown by small black dots on the map.

The boundaries of many geothermal anomalies lack precise control because of uneven data coverage. In areas of sparse data, hot spring temperature data were used to supplement the available gradient data.  A relationship between spring temperature and expected gradient value was derived by plotting hot spring temperature (Cappa and Hemborg, 1995) against nearby drill hole gradient data for the Hortense, Cottonwood, Pagosa, and Shaws hot springs.  The resulting least-squares best-fit linear equation, G = 2.181T - 24.80, allows a rough estimate of geothermal gradient, G, using hot spring temperatures, T, in Colorado's mountainous areas where down-hole temperature values are not available.  Contour lines are dashed where values derived from hot springs influence the contour placement.

Geothermal gradients are calculated by two primary techniques.  If multiple temperature-depth measurements are available from a single drillhole or well, the longest section of measurements is taken in which the data define an approximately linear plot.  The gradient is calculated as a linear least-squares fit to this sub-set of the data.  This is the preferred method of gradient calculation and was used on a limited number of wells for which temperature log data were acquired.  For most wells, only one down-hole temperature was available.  To derive geothermal gradient in these cases, an estimate of the surface ground temperature was made based on mean annual air surface temperature.  The average geothermal gradient in the hole is then given by the difference between the down-hole temperature and the surface ground temperature, divided by the depth to the temperature measurement point.
</abstract>
			<purpose>For representation of gradient datapoints and interpretation of zones of equal gradient in Colorado.</purpose>
			<supplinf>
Gradient data source references:
Blackwell, D., and Richards, M., 1989, Regional heat flow database (Colorado), SMU Geothermal Lab - Geothermal Data Files, data file: Color89.csv, &lt;http://www.smu.edu/geothermal/georesou/colorado.htm&gt; Accessed May 3, 2006.

International Heat Flow Commission, Global Heat Flow Database, International Association of Seismology and Physics of the Earth's Interior, site Provided by the University of North Dakota, data file: USA.xls, &lt;http://www.heatflow.und.edu&gt; Accessed May 3, 2006.
</supplinf>
			<langdata Sync="TRUE">en</langdata></descript>
		<timeperd>
			<timeinfo>
				<sngdate>
					<caldate>October 2007</caldate>
				</sngdate>
			</timeinfo>
			<current>ground condition</current>
		</timeperd>
		<status>
			<progress>Complete</progress>
			<update>None planned</update>
		</status>
		<spdom>
			<bounding>
				<westbc Sync="TRUE">-109.275474</westbc>
				<eastbc Sync="TRUE">-101.871924</eastbc>
				<northbc Sync="TRUE">41.057033</northbc>
				<southbc Sync="TRUE">36.927980</southbc>
			</bounding>
			<lboundng><leftbc Sync="TRUE">140257.529080</leftbc><rightbc Sync="TRUE">763036.406464</rightbc><bottombc Sync="TRUE">4094507.243771</bottombc><topbc Sync="TRUE">4545088.278163</topbc></lboundng></spdom>
		<keywords>
			<theme>
				<themekey>geothermal</themekey>
				<themekey>gradient</themekey>
				<themekey>datapoints</themekey>
				<themekt>REQUIRED: Reference to a formally registered thesaurus or a similar authoritative source of theme keywords.</themekt></theme>
			<place>
				<placekey>Colorado</placekey>
			</place>
			<temporal>
				<tempkey>2007</tempkey>
			</temporal>
		</keywords>
		<accconst>None.</accconst>
		<useconst>The Colorado Department of Natural Resources ("DNR") is not responsible and shall not be liable to the user for damages of any kind arising out of the use of data or information provided by the DNR, including the installation of the data or information, its use, or the results obtained from its use. ANY DATA OR INFORMATION PROVIDED BY THE DNR IS PROVIDED "AS IS" WITHOUT WARRANTY OF ANY KIND, EITHER EXPRESS OR IMPLIED, INCLUDING, BUT NOT LIMITED TO, THE IMPLIED WARRANTIES OF MERCHANTABILITY AND FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE. Data or information provided by the DNR shall be used and relied upon only at the user's sole risk, and the user agrees to indemnify and hold harmless the DNR, its officials, officers and employees from any liability arising out of the use of the data/information provided.</useconst>
		<ptcontac>
			<cntinfo>
				<cntorgp>
					<cntorg>Colorado Geological Survey</cntorg>
				</cntorgp>
				<cntaddr>
					<addrtype>mailing and physical address</addrtype>
					<address>1313 Sherman St, #715</address>
					<city>Denver</city>
					<state>Colorado</state>
					<postal>80203</postal>
					<country>USA</country>
				</cntaddr>
				<cntvoice>303-866-2611</cntvoice>
			</cntinfo>
		</ptcontac>
		<native Sync="TRUE">Microsoft Windows XP Version 5.1 (Build 2600) Service Pack 2; ESRI ArcCatalog 9.3.1.1850</native>
		<natvform Sync="TRUE">Shapefile</natvform></idinfo>
	<dataqual>
		<lineage>
			<srcinfo>
				<typesrc>online</typesrc>
				<srccitea>Blackwell, D., and Richards, M., 1989, Regional heat flow database (Colorado), SMU Geothermal Lab - Geothermal Data Files, data file: Color89.csv, &lt;http://www.smu.edu/geothermal/georesou/colorado.htm&gt; Accessed May 3, 2006.</srccitea>
			</srcinfo>
			<srcinfo>
				<typesrc>online</typesrc>
				<srccitea>International Heat Flow Commission, Global Heat Flow Database, International Association of Seismology and Physics of the Earth's Interior, site Provided by the University of North Dakota, data file: USA.xls, &lt;http://www.heatflow.und.edu&gt; Accessed May 3, 2006.</srccitea>
			</srcinfo>
			<procstep>
				<procdesc>Well data were assembled from various data sources and gradient values were calculated for each datapoint in accordance with the methodology described in the abstract and in the Map Series 46 report text depending on the type of data source. 
----------
Gradients calculated from bottom-hole temperatures include those records with the data source designation "BHT - Dixon" and "BHT - CGS/MJS". "BHT - Dixon" data was calculated using data compiled from two sources 1) "Dixon, J., 2002, Evaluation of bottom-hole temperatures in the Denver and San Juan basins of Colorado: Colorado Geological Survey Open-File Report 02-15, 41 p." and 2) "Dixon, J., 2004, Evaluation of bottom-hole temperatures in the Canon City Embayment, Hugoton Embayment, North Park, Paradox, Piceance, Raton, and Sand Wash basins of Colorado: Colorado Geological Survey Open-File Report 04-1, 44 p." 

"BHT - CGS/MJS" data was calculated by the CGS from bottom-hole temperature data extracted out of M.J. Systems' Log Sleuth software. 
----------
Gradients calculated from drill-stem test data include those with the data source designation "DST - IHS". "DST - IHS" data was calculated using data assembled from IHS Energy's PI Dwights software. 
----------
Gradients calculated from temperature log data include those points with the data souce designation "CGS - MS45/Log" and "CGS - other/Log". "CGS - MS45/Log" data was calculated by the CGS  from temperature logs acquired by the CGS for the Map Series 45, Interpretive Geothermal Heat Flow Map of Colorado publication. 

"CGS - other/Log" data was calculated by CGS using additional temperature log data.
----------
Gradient datapoints with the designation  "CGS - MS45/other HF databases" was assembled by others from various heat flow data references and have unknown calculation methods.  

"CGS - MS45/other HF databases" is data included in the Map Series 45 heat flow publication and was assembled from two heat flow databases: 1) Blackwell and Richards (1989) Regional Heat Flow Database for Colorado and 2) International Heat Flow Commission, Global Heat Flow Database. 

Background well data information was extracted from the Colorado Oil and Gas Conservation Commission (COGCC) well database (dated June 2008) using API number to include with the calculated gradient values. Some API numbers were not present in the COGCC database and therefore only contain some of the background information.

Gradient data sources:
Blackwell, D., and Richards, M., 1989, Regional heat flow database (Colorado), SMU Geothermal Lab - Geothermal Data Files, data file: Color89.csv, &lt;http://www.smu.edu/geothermal/georesou/colorado.htm&gt; Accessed May 3, 2006.

International Heat Flow Commission, Global Heat Flow Database, International Association of Seismology and Physics of the Earth's Interior, site Provided by the University of North Dakota, data file: USA.xls, &lt;http://www.heatflow.und.edu&gt; Accessed May 3, 2006.</procdesc>
			</procstep>
		</lineage>
	</dataqual>
	<spdoinfo>
		<direct Sync="TRUE">Vector</direct>
		<ptvctinf>
			<sdtsterm Name="Colorado_Geothermal_Gradient_Datapoints">
				<sdtstype Sync="TRUE">Entity point</sdtstype>
				<ptvctcnt Sync="TRUE">17053</ptvctcnt>
			</sdtsterm>
			<esriterm Name="Colorado_Geothermal_Gradient_Datapoints"><efeatyp Sync="TRUE">Simple</efeatyp><efeageom Sync="TRUE">Point</efeageom><esritopo Sync="TRUE">FALSE</esritopo><efeacnt Sync="TRUE">17053</efeacnt><spindex Sync="TRUE">TRUE</spindex><linrefer Sync="TRUE">FALSE</linrefer></esriterm></ptvctinf>
	</spdoinfo>
	<spref>
		<horizsys>
			<planar>
				<planci>
					<plance Sync="TRUE">coordinate pair</plance>
					<coordrep>
						<absres Sync="TRUE">0.000000</absres>
						<ordres Sync="TRUE">0.000000</ordres>
					</coordrep>
					<plandu Sync="TRUE">meters</plandu>
				</planci>
				<gridsys><gridsysn Sync="TRUE">Universal Transverse Mercator</gridsysn><utm><utmzone Sync="TRUE">13</utmzone><transmer><sfctrmer Sync="TRUE">0.999600</sfctrmer><longcm Sync="TRUE">-105.000000</longcm><latprjo Sync="TRUE">0.000000</latprjo><feast Sync="TRUE">500000.000000</feast><fnorth Sync="TRUE">0.000000</fnorth></transmer></utm></gridsys></planar>
			<geodetic>
				<horizdn Sync="TRUE">North American Datum of 1983</horizdn>
				<ellips Sync="TRUE">Geodetic Reference System 80</ellips>
				<semiaxis Sync="TRUE">6378137.000000</semiaxis>
				<denflat Sync="TRUE">298.257222</denflat>
			</geodetic>
			<cordsysn><geogcsn Sync="TRUE">GCS_North_American_1983</geogcsn><projcsn Sync="TRUE">NAD_1983_UTM_Zone_13N</projcsn></cordsysn></horizsys>
		<vertdef>
			<altsys>
				<altres>0.000100</altres>
				<altenc>Explicit elevation coordinate included with horizontal coordinates</altenc>
			</altsys>
		</vertdef>
	</spref>
	<eainfo>
		<detailed Name="Colorado_Geothermal_Gradient_Datapoints">
			<enttyp>
				<enttypl Sync="TRUE">Colorado_Geothermal_Gradient_Datapoints</enttypl>
				<enttypt Sync="TRUE">Feature Class</enttypt><enttypc Sync="TRUE">17053</enttypc></enttyp>
			<attr><attrlabl Sync="TRUE">FID</attrlabl><attalias Sync="TRUE">FID</attalias><attrtype Sync="TRUE">OID</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">4</attwidth><atprecis Sync="TRUE">0</atprecis><attscale Sync="TRUE">0</attscale><attrdef Sync="TRUE">Internal feature number.</attrdef><attrdefs Sync="TRUE">ESRI</attrdefs><attrdomv><udom Sync="TRUE">Sequential unique whole numbers that are automatically generated.</udom></attrdomv></attr><attr>
				<attrlabl>Shape</attrlabl>
				<attrdef>Feature geometry.</attrdef>
				<attrdefs>ESRI</attrdefs>
				<attrdomv>
					<udom>Coordinates defining the features.</udom>
				</attrdomv>
				<attalias Sync="TRUE">Shape</attalias><attrtype Sync="TRUE">Geometry</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">0</attwidth><atprecis Sync="TRUE">0</atprecis><attscale Sync="TRUE">0</attscale></attr>
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>Well_Name</attrlabl>
				<attrdef>Well or borehole name; composite of Facility name and number attributes</attrdef>
				<attrdefs>CGS</attrdefs>
				<attalias Sync="TRUE">Well_Name</attalias><attrtype Sync="TRUE">String</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">254</attwidth></attr>
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>Operator_N</attrlabl>
				<attrdef>Well or borehole operator name</attrdef>
				<attrdefs>CGS</attrdefs>
				<attalias Sync="TRUE">Operator_N</attalias><attrtype Sync="TRUE">String</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">254</attwidth></attr>
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>Facility_N</attrlabl>
				<attrdef>Facility (well) name</attrdef>
				<attrdefs>CGS</attrdefs>
				<attalias Sync="TRUE">Facility_N</attalias><attrtype Sync="TRUE">String</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">254</attwidth></attr>
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>Facility_1</attrlabl>
				<attrdef>Facility (well) number</attrdef>
				<attrdefs>CGS</attrdefs>
				<attalias Sync="TRUE">Facility_1</attalias><attrtype Sync="TRUE">String</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">254</attwidth></attr>
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>API_Number</attrlabl>
				<attrdef>American Petroleum Institute unique well identifier</attrdef>
				<attrdefs>CGS</attrdefs>
				<attalias Sync="TRUE">API_Number</attalias><attrtype Sync="TRUE">String</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">254</attwidth></attr>
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>Gradient_C</attrlabl>
				<attrdef>Calculated vertical geothermal gradient value in degrees Celsius per kilometer. Gradient values were calculated in accordance with the methodology discussed in the abstract and Map Series 46 report text depending on the data source type. The gradient data source type is indicated in the "Gradient Data Source" attribute field. Bottom-hole temperature and drill-stem test data employed a gradient calculation method by linearly interpolating between the Gradient Reference Depth of the bottom-hole or drill-stem test temperature measurement and the calculated ground surface temperature. Gradient values for temperature log gradient values were generated by a best-fit method to a temperature-logged borehole section. If temperature log data is present for multiple borehole sections then the average gradient of these sections is used.</attrdef>
				<attrdefs>CGS</attrdefs>
				<attalias Sync="TRUE">Gradient_C</attalias><attrtype Sync="TRUE">Float</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">19</attwidth></attr>
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>Gradient_R</attrlabl>
				<attrdef>Reference depth below the surface over which the gradient value was calculated. For gradients calculated from bottom-hole temperature data, this depth represents the total borehole or well depth; for gradients calculated from drill-stem test data this represents the mid-point depth of the deepest drill-stem test; for gradients calculated from temperature log data this depth represents the deepest log interval available.</attrdef>
				<attrdefs>CGS</attrdefs>
				<attalias Sync="TRUE">Gradient_R</attalias><attrtype Sync="TRUE">Float</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">19</attwidth></attr>
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>Total_Dept</attrlabl>
				<attrdef>Total borehole or well depth, if available.</attrdef>
				<attrdefs>CGS</attrdefs>
				<attalias Sync="TRUE">Total_Dept</attalias><attrtype Sync="TRUE">Float</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">19</attwidth></attr>
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>Gradient_D</attrlabl>
				<attrdef>Type of data source from which gradient was calculated. Gradients calculated from bottom-hole temperatures include those records with the designation "BHT - Dixon" and "BHT - CGS/MJS"; gradients calculated from drill-stem test data include those with the designation "DST - IHS"; gradients calculated from temperature log data include those points with the designations "CGS - MS45/Log" and "CGS - Other/Log". Gradient datapoints with the designation "CGS - MS45/other HF databases" have various calculation methods because they were assembled from several heat flow databases by other researchers. "BHT - Dixon" data was calculated using data from the Regional Heat Flow Database for Colorado by Blackwell and Richards (1989). "BHT - CGS/MJS" data was calculated by the CGS from data extracted out of M.J. Systems' Log Sleuth software. "DST - IHS" data was calculated using data assembled from IHS Energy's PI Dwights software. "CGS - MS45/Log" data was calculated by the CGS  from temperature logs acquired by the CGS for the Map Series 45, Interpretive Geothermal Heat Flow Map of Colorado publication. "CGS - MS45/other HF databases" is data included in the Map Series 45 heat flow publication and was assembled from two heat flow databases which compiled data from various references: 1) Blackwell and Richards (1989) Regional Heat Flow Database for Colorado and 2) International Heat Flow Commission, Global Heat Flow Database. Heat flow data are generally acquired from temperature logs. The original heat flow data for these points can be found in the MS 45 publication. "CGS - Other/Log" data was calculated by CGS using temperature log data.</attrdef>
				<attrdefs>CGS</attrdefs>
				<attrdomv>
					<edom>
						<edomv>BHT Dixon</edomv>
					</edom>
				</attrdomv>
				<attalias Sync="TRUE">Gradient_D</attalias><attrtype Sync="TRUE">String</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">254</attwidth></attr>
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>Bottom_Hol</attrlabl>
				<attrdef>Bottom-hole temperature measurement in degrees Celcius.</attrdef>
				<attrdefs>CGS</attrdefs>
				<attalias Sync="TRUE">Bottom_Hol</attalias><attrtype Sync="TRUE">Float</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">19</attwidth></attr>
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>Drill_Stem</attrlabl>
				<attrdef>Drill-stem test temperature measurement in degrees Celcius from IHS Energy - PI/Dwights.</attrdef>
				<attrdefs>CGS</attrdefs>
				<attalias Sync="TRUE">Drill_Stem</attalias><attrtype Sync="TRUE">String</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">50</attwidth></attr>
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>Completed_</attrlabl>
				<attrdef>Completed geologic formation</attrdef>
				<attrdefs>CGS</attrdefs>
				<attalias Sync="TRUE">Completed_</attalias><attrtype Sync="TRUE">String</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">254</attwidth></attr>
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>Surface_El</attrlabl>
				<attrdef>Calculated surface elevation in meters from 30-meter resolution digital elevation model (DEM) based on locational coordinates provided for datapoint.</attrdef>
				<attrdefs>CGS</attrdefs>
				<attalias Sync="TRUE">Surface_El</attalias><attrtype Sync="TRUE">Float</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">19</attwidth></attr>
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>Mean_Air_T</attrlabl>
				<attrdef>Mean annual air temperature in degrees Celcius (+/- 1.1 deg C) extracted from PRISM climate model GIS data. Air surface temperatures at each well were derived from the PRISM model data from Oregon State University (Daly, C., and Gibson, W., 2006, United States average monthly or annual minimum, maximum, and mean temperature, 1971-2000, &lt;http://www.climatesource.com/us/fact_sheets/meta_tmin_us_71b.html#7&gt; Accessed September 3, 2008.).  This model was used to generate contours of mean annual air surface temperature for Colorado at intervals of 2ºF.  The air surface temperature at each well site was then determined from these contours using GIS techniques and the geographical coordinates of each well.  Three degrees Celsius was added to each calculated air temperature to give the ground surface temperature at each site to compensate for the difference between air and ground temperatures associated with radiative ground heating and other effects.</attrdef>
				<attrdefs>CGS</attrdefs>
				<attalias Sync="TRUE">Mean_Air_T</attalias><attrtype Sync="TRUE">Float</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">19</attwidth></attr>
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>Ground_Sur</attrlabl>
				<attrdef>Calculated ground surface temperature in degrees Celcius used in the calculation of gradient values for bottom-hole temperature and drill-stem test data. The ground surface temperature was calculated from the mean annual air temperature by adding 3 degrees Celcius to each calculated air temperature to compensate for the difference between air and ground temperatures associated with radiative ground heating and other effects.</attrdef>
				<attalias Sync="TRUE">Ground_Sur</attalias><attrtype Sync="TRUE">Float</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">19</attwidth></attr>
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>Latitude</attrlabl>
				<attrdef>Latitude in decimal degrees (North American Datum 1983)</attrdef>
				<attrdefs>CGS</attrdefs>
				<attalias Sync="TRUE">Latitude</attalias><attrtype Sync="TRUE">Float</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">19</attwidth></attr>
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>Longitude</attrlabl>
				<attrdef>Longitude in decimal degrees (North American Datum 1983)</attrdef>
				<attrdefs>CGS</attrdefs>
				<attalias Sync="TRUE">Longitude</attalias><attrtype Sync="TRUE">Float</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">19</attwidth></attr>
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>UTM83_X</attrlabl>
				<attrdef>Easting coordinate in meters (Universal Transverse Mercator, North American Datum 1983, Zone 13N)</attrdef>
				<attrdefs>CGS</attrdefs>
				<attalias Sync="TRUE">UTM83_X</attalias><attrtype Sync="TRUE">Float</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">19</attwidth></attr>
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>UTM83_Y</attrlabl>
				<attrdef>Northing coordinate in meters (Universal Transverse Mercator, North American Datum 1983, Zone 13N)</attrdef>
				<attrdefs>CGS</attrdefs>
				<attalias Sync="TRUE">UTM83_Y</attalias><attrtype Sync="TRUE">Float</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">19</attwidth></attr>
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>Basin_Tect</attrlabl>
				<attrdef>Oil and gas basin or tectonic province</attrdef>
				<attrdefs>CGS</attrdefs>
				<attalias Sync="TRUE">Basin_Tect</attalias><attrtype Sync="TRUE">String</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">254</attwidth></attr>
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>Field_Loca</attrlabl>
				<attrdef>Oil and gas field</attrdef>
				<attrdefs>CGS</attrdefs>
				<attalias Sync="TRUE">Field_Loca</attalias><attrtype Sync="TRUE">String</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">254</attwidth></attr>
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>County</attrlabl>
				<attrdef>County name</attrdef>
				<attrdefs>CGS</attrdefs>
				<attalias Sync="TRUE">County</attalias><attrtype Sync="TRUE">String</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">254</attwidth></attr>
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>Township</attrlabl>
				<attrdef>PLSS township number and direction</attrdef>
				<attrdefs>CGS</attrdefs>
				<attalias Sync="TRUE">Township</attalias><attrtype Sync="TRUE">String</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">254</attwidth></attr>
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>Range</attrlabl>
				<attrdef>PLSS range number and direction</attrdef>
				<attrdefs>CGS</attrdefs>
				<attalias Sync="TRUE">Range</attalias><attrtype Sync="TRUE">String</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">254</attwidth></attr>
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>Section_Nu</attrlabl>
				<attrdef>PLSS section number</attrdef>
				<attrdefs>CGS</attrdefs>
				<attalias Sync="TRUE">Section_Nu</attalias><attrtype Sync="TRUE">Float</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">19</attwidth></attr>
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>Qtr_Qtr</attrlabl>
				<attrdef>PLSS section quarter-quarter</attrdef>
				<attrdefs>CGS</attrdefs>
				<attalias Sync="TRUE">Qtr_Qtr</attalias><attrtype Sync="TRUE">String</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">254</attwidth></attr>
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>Meridian</attrlabl>
				<attrdef>PLSS applicable meridian</attrdef>
				<attrdefs>CGS</attrdefs>
				<attalias Sync="TRUE">Meridian</attalias><attrtype Sync="TRUE">String</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">254</attwidth></attr>
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>Feet_E_W</attrlabl>
				<attrdef>Point location distance, in feet, from the east or west PLSS section line </attrdef>
				<attrdefs>CGS</attrdefs>
				<attalias Sync="TRUE">Feet_E_W</attalias><attrtype Sync="TRUE">Float</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">19</attwidth></attr>
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>Direction_</attrlabl>
				<attrdef>East or west PLSS section line from which the point location distance is measured</attrdef>
				<attrdefs>CGS</attrdefs>
				<attalias Sync="TRUE">Direction_</attalias><attrtype Sync="TRUE">String</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">254</attwidth></attr>
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>Feet_N_S</attrlabl>
				<attrdef>Point location distance, in feet, from the north or south PLSS section line</attrdef>
				<attrdefs>CGS</attrdefs>
				<attalias Sync="TRUE">Feet_N_S</attalias><attrtype Sync="TRUE">Float</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">19</attwidth></attr>
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>Direction1</attrlabl>
				<attrdef>North or south PLSS section line from which the point location distance is measured</attrdef>
				<attrdefs>CGS</attrdefs>
				<attalias Sync="TRUE">Direction1</attalias><attrtype Sync="TRUE">String</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">254</attwidth></attr>
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>Well_Bore_</attrlabl>
				<attrdef>Oil and gas well or borehole status, from COGCC database.  Abandoned (AB); Active (AC) ; Abandoned location (AL); Comingled (CM); Domestic well (DM); Drilling (DG); Dry and abandoned (DA); Injecting (IJ); Permit to deepen for injection (PD); Plugged and abandoned (PA); Producing (PR); Shut In (SI); Temporarily abandoned (TA); Unitized (UN); Verbal Intent to plug (VP); Waiting on completion (WO); Permit (XX)  </attrdef>
				<attrdefs>CGS/COGCC</attrdefs>
				<attalias Sync="TRUE">Well_Bore_</attalias><attrtype Sync="TRUE">String</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">254</attwidth></attr>
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>Status_Dat</attrlabl>
				<attrdef>Date of oil and gas well or borehole status designation</attrdef>
				<attrdefs>CGS</attrdefs>
				<attalias Sync="TRUE">Status_Dat</attalias><attrtype Sync="TRUE">Date</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">8</attwidth></attr>
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>Spud_Drill</attrlabl>
				<attrdef>Spud date (date of drilling commencement) from COGCC database or other drilled date provided</attrdef>
				<attrdefs>CGS</attrdefs>
				<attalias Sync="TRUE">Spud_Drill</attalias><attrtype Sync="TRUE">Date</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">8</attwidth></attr>
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>Temp_3000f</attrlabl>
				<attrdef>Projected temperature in degrees Fahrenheit at a depth of 3000 feet below ground surface based on datapoint gradient value</attrdef>
				<attrdefs>CGS</attrdefs>
				<attalias Sync="TRUE">Temp_3000f</attalias><attrtype Sync="TRUE">Number</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">4</attwidth></attr>
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>Temp_6000f</attrlabl>
				<attrdef>Projected temperature in degrees Fahrenheit at a depth of 6000 feet below ground surface based on datapoint gradient value</attrdef>
				<attrdefs>CGS</attrdefs>
				<attalias Sync="TRUE">Temp_6000f</attalias><attrtype Sync="TRUE">Number</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">4</attwidth></attr>
			<attr><attrlabl Sync="TRUE">Temp_10000</attrlabl><attalias Sync="TRUE">Temp_10000</attalias><attrtype Sync="TRUE">Number</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">4</attwidth></attr><attr>
				<attrlabl>Depth_Boil</attrlabl>
				<attrdef>Projected depth in feet below ground surface to boiling water based on datapoint gradient value and assuming standard atmospheric pressure.</attrdef>
				<attrdefs>CGS</attrdefs>
				<attalias Sync="TRUE">Depth_Boil</attalias><attrtype Sync="TRUE">Number</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">9</attwidth></attr>
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>Temp_3km_C</attrlabl>
				<attrdef>Projected temperature in degrees Celsius at a depth of 3 kilometers below ground surface based on datapoint gradient value</attrdef>
				<attrdefs>CGS</attrdefs>
				<attalias Sync="TRUE">Temp_3km_C</attalias><attrtype Sync="TRUE">Number</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">4</attwidth></attr>
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>Temp_5km_C</attrlabl>
				<attrdef>Projected temperature in degrees Celsius at a depth of 5 kilometers below ground surface based on datapoint gradient value</attrdef>
				<attrdefs>CGS</attrdefs>
				<attalias Sync="TRUE">Temp_5km_C</attalias><attrtype Sync="TRUE">Number</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">4</attwidth></attr>
		</detailed>
		<detailed>
			<enttyp>
				<enttypl>Anno_30_36</enttypl>
			</enttyp>
			<attr><atnumdec/></attr><attr><atnumdec/></attr><attr/><attr/><attr/><attr/><attr/><attr><atnumdec/></attr><attr><atnumdec/></attr><attr><atnumdec/></attr><attr/><attr><atnumdec/></attr><attr/><attr/><attr><atnumdec Sync="TRUE">11</atnumdec></attr><attr><atnumdec Sync="TRUE">11</atnumdec></attr><attr><atnumdec Sync="TRUE">11</atnumdec></attr><attr><atnumdec Sync="TRUE">11</atnumdec></attr><attr><atnumdec Sync="TRUE">11</atnumdec></attr><attr><atnumdec Sync="TRUE">11</atnumdec></attr><attr><atnumdec Sync="TRUE">11</atnumdec></attr><attr/><attr/><attr/><attr/><attr/><attr><atnumdec/></attr><attr/><attr/><attr><atnumdec Sync="TRUE">11</atnumdec></attr><attr/><attr><atnumdec Sync="TRUE">11</atnumdec></attr></detailed>
	</eainfo>
	<distinfo>
		<resdesc>Downloadable Data</resdesc>
		<stdorder>
			<digform>
				<digtinfo>
					<transize>12.565</transize>
					<dssize Sync="TRUE">0.455</dssize></digtinfo>
			</digform>
		</stdorder>
	</distinfo>
	<metainfo>
		<metd Sync="TRUE">20081224</metd>
		<metc>
			<cntinfo>
				<cntorgp>
					<cntorg>Colorado Geological Survey</cntorg>
					<cntper>REQUIRED: The person responsible for the metadata information.</cntper></cntorgp>
				<cntaddr>
					<addrtype>mailing and physical address</addrtype>
					<address>1313 Sherman St, #715</address>
					<city>Denver</city>
					<state>Colorado</state>
					<postal>80203</postal>
					<country>USA</country>
				</cntaddr>
				<cntvoice>303-866-2611</cntvoice>
			</cntinfo>
		</metc>
		<metstdn Sync="TRUE">FGDC Content Standards for Digital Geospatial Metadata</metstdn>
		<metstdv Sync="TRUE">FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv>
		<mettc Sync="TRUE">local time</mettc>
		<metextns>
			<onlink>http://www.esri.com/metadata/esriprof80.html</onlink>
			<metprof>ESRI Metadata Profile</metprof>
		</metextns>
		<metextns>
			<onlink>http://www.esri.com/metadata/esriprof80.html</onlink>
			<metprof>ESRI Metadata Profile</metprof>
		</metextns>
		<metextns>
			<onlink>http://www.esri.com/metadata/esriprof80.html</onlink>
			<metprof>ESRI Metadata Profile</metprof>
		</metextns>
		<langmeta Sync="TRUE">en</langmeta><metextns><onlink Sync="TRUE">http://www.esri.com/metadata/esriprof80.html</onlink><metprof Sync="TRUE">ESRI Metadata Profile</metprof></metextns></metainfo>
	<Esri><CreaDate>20081217</CreaDate><CreaTime>09541500</CreaTime><SyncOnce>FALSE</SyncOnce><SyncDate>20081224</SyncDate><SyncTime>09280400</SyncTime><ModDate>20081224</ModDate><ModTime>09300300</ModTime><MetaID>{81FA3F02-2B4D-455F-AB92-FA8090619B52}</MetaID></Esri><dataIdInfo><envirDesc Sync="TRUE">Microsoft Windows XP Version 5.1 (Build 2600) Service Pack 2; ESRI ArcCatalog 9.3.1.1850</envirDesc><dataLang><languageCode Sync="TRUE" value="en"></languageCode></dataLang><idCitation><resTitle Sync="TRUE">Colorado_Geothermal_Gradient_Datapoints</resTitle><presForm><PresFormCd Sync="TRUE" value="005"></PresFormCd></presForm></idCitation><spatRpType><SpatRepTypCd Sync="TRUE" value="001"></SpatRepTypCd></spatRpType><dataExt><geoEle><GeoBndBox esriExtentType="native"><westBL Sync="TRUE">140257.52908</westBL><eastBL Sync="TRUE">763036.406464</eastBL><northBL Sync="TRUE">4545088.278163</northBL><southBL Sync="TRUE">4094507.243771</southBL><exTypeCode Sync="TRUE">1</exTypeCode></GeoBndBox></geoEle></dataExt><geoBox esriExtentType="decdegrees"><westBL Sync="TRUE">-109.275474</westBL><eastBL Sync="TRUE">-101.871924</eastBL><northBL Sync="TRUE">41.057033</northBL><southBL Sync="TRUE">36.92798</southBL><exTypeCode Sync="TRUE">1</exTypeCode></geoBox></dataIdInfo><mdLang><languageCode Sync="TRUE" value="en"></languageCode></mdLang><mdStanName Sync="TRUE">ISO 19115 Geographic Information - Metadata</mdStanName><mdStanVer Sync="TRUE">DIS_ESRI1.0</mdStanVer><mdChar><CharSetCd Sync="TRUE" value="004"></CharSetCd></mdChar><mdHrLv><ScopeCd Sync="TRUE" value="005"></ScopeCd></mdHrLv><mdHrLvName Sync="TRUE">dataset</mdHrLvName><distInfo><distributor><distorTran><onLineSrc><orDesc Sync="TRUE">002</orDesc><linkage Sync="TRUE">file://\\CGS-6YQQKF1-LXP\C$\Documents and Settings\WatterNi\My Documents\CGS Projects\Geothermal\MS46 Gradient Map Publication\Final Publication\CD contents\GIS data\Shapefiles\Colorado_Geothermal_Gradient_Datapoints.shp</linkage><protocol Sync="TRUE">Local Area Network</protocol></onLineSrc><transSize Sync="TRUE">0.455</transSize></distorTran><distorFormat><formatName Sync="TRUE">Shapefile</formatName></distorFormat></distributor></distInfo><refSysInfo><RefSystem><refSysID><identCode Sync="TRUE">NAD_1983_UTM_Zone_13N</identCode></refSysID></RefSystem></refSysInfo><spatRepInfo><VectSpatRep><topLvl><TopoLevCd Sync="TRUE" value="001"></TopoLevCd></topLvl><geometObjs Name="Colorado_Geothermal_Gradient_Datapoints"><geoObjTyp><GeoObjTypCd Sync="TRUE" value="004"></GeoObjTypCd></geoObjTyp><geoObjCnt Sync="TRUE">17053</geoObjCnt></geometObjs></VectSpatRep></spatRepInfo><mdDateSt Sync="TRUE">20081224</mdDateSt></metadata>
